this video is sponsored by brilliant hey
guys this looks like a fun one we're
given that these three angles are equal
and it wants to know what fraction of
the entire rectangle is shaded if you
want to try it on your own pause it
right now cuz I'm going to solve it in 3
2 1 first since it's a rectangle we know
all these angles are right angles this
is a 90° angle up here and since all
these angles are equal each of them has
to be 30° next let's look at this top
triangle if this is 30 and this is 90
this angle has to be 60 and same thing
for this lower triangle if this angle's
30 this one's 90 this one has to be 60°
since both of these are 30 6090
triangles let's look at the notes for
306090 triangles in every 306090
triangle the hypotenuse is always twice
as big as the shortest side and to get
the length of the side opposite the 60°
you multiply the shortest side by the
square < TK of 3 and this is always true
for every single 30 6090 triangle so how
are we going to use these notes if we
don't have any side lengths we can
assign the variable X to this piece
right here so we can take our triangle
out and to find this length we can take
our shortest side and multiply it by
square < TK of three now let's bring the
triangle back up here we have this piece
in terms of X and we have the height of
our entire rectangle in terms of X and
in a rectangle opposite sides are
congruent so this side is also X < tk3
now let's pull this triangle out and
let's find the length of this side in
terms of X we're going to take this xk3
and multiply it by S < TK of 3 so we end
up with x < tk3 * < tk3 < tk3 * < tk3 is
equal to < TK of 9 and theun of 9 is
equal to 3 so this side length is equal
to 3x so let's bring this triangle back
up here now looking at this rectangle we
have both the height and the width in
terms of X since we know the whole width
is 3x and this piece is X that means
this piece is equal to 2X and now we're
ready to answer the question we want to
do the Shaded area divided by the total
area the Shaded area is this triangle
it's going to be 1/2 base time height so
it's 1/2 * the base of 2x * the height
of X < tk3 and then to get the total
area of the rectangle we're going do
base time height the base is equal to 3x
and the height is equal to X < tk3 and
now we can clean this up a little bit
this 1/2 * this 2 is equal to one and
this xk3 and this xk3 are going to
cancel each other out so now we have 1 X
over 3x well these two x's will also
cancel each other out now we have the
answer to our question 1/3 of this
entire rectangle is shaded let's put a
box around it I really like this problem
I thought it was brilliant speaking of
brilliant let me give you an update on
Brilliance I went through this
predicting with probability I love to
use historical data to form probability
distributions about future events it's
such a cool concept make predictions
about weather medicine traffic even
artificial intelligence this is what I
was looking forward to the most the Bas
theorem stuff I think they chose a
really good example for the lesson and
then I love the practice problems for
each of the problems they had a hint and
a full explanation I found it fun to
First not use the formula and just see
if I could logically deduce what would
occur and then I use the formula to
verify it I don't want to go through too
much detail in case you want to go
through it yourself speaking of going
through it yourself if you want to try
out brilliant there's a free 30-day
trial visit brilliant.org animath or
click on the link in the description you
can also get 20% off an annual premium
plan how exciting